Hey, and welcome back to Living in
[music] Central Texas. I'm Andrea Dudik,
your local expert to all things real
estate here in the Central Texas area.
[music]
Today, I'll be giving you a really great
look at what around $400,000
can buy you in three of our best [music]
suburbs, especially if you're
relocating. We'll be looking at Troy,
Nolanville, and Little River Academy.
[music]
Last week in our last episode, Matt and
I, my uh partner, we drove around these
three suburbs, [music]
giving you a really great glimpse into
the roads, the areas, lifestyles,
community. Um, everything from an
exterior view of those suburbs. But
today, [music] we're going to give you
the inside look at some really awesome
homes so you can compare what that same
price point looks like in three
different areas. Now, if you're new to
the channel [music] and you find this
video helpful, I post a lot of really
great information on relocating to the
area. [music] So, don't forget to like,
subscribe, and click the bell
notification so that you can stay up to
date on all things real estate here in
central Texas.
[music]
We're currently in the Turtle Creek
subdivision in Troy. This is [music]
their newest community um or one of
their newer communities. It's their more
luxury community, [music] I would say.
And a lot of really great builders in
here. The house that we're about [music]
to take a look at, I've done a lot of
content on just because they do a really
beautiful home. Really great quality and
craftsmanship and variety of price
points. [music] If you love this home,
make sure to check out the video I
recently did on Stenant Mills and Theo.
Um, I highlighted their higherend price
points [music] in the low700s.
This one is priced at $399.
They just did a price drop on it,
[music]
offering a ton of incentives. If you
want to know what those are, give me a
call, but it's a four bed, two bath, um,
just over 2100 square ft built in 2025.
Let's go take a look.
I actually did a video on Troy not long
ago and I think I did this video.
[music] I mean this house, but we'll
take a look at it in this video. But
really pretty brick [music]
fireplace. He did an electric fireplace
in this one. All of the color [music]
schemes in this one are going to be more
brown, warmer toned. They do a lot of
this wood [music] like ceramic tile
flooring. So, it looks like wood, but
it's really tile. Super durable. Um, and
[music] it's actually an upgrade if
you're comparing it to like luxury vinyl
plank or something like that because it
costs more and it costs more for them to
lay down the tile. And [music] some
other things that I really love about
this builder, as you can really tell
from their kitchens, [music] is that
they include hardware. These are
typically going to be soft closed
drawers
and they do like thicker countertops.
This is granite, [music] but they do a
lot of quartz in their properties. um
stainless steel [music] appliances
and they actually have a whole design
center which not all of the builders do
locally. So I really love that they have
a whole team designated to staying
trendy and up to date on what's really
beautiful and aesthetically appealing uh
for our for our time. So, we have this
tan square uh tile backsplash,
2100 square ft. [music]
It It still sells pretty big and open.
Um [music] you'll see that this builder
does a lot of really great light
fixtures. This home does include blinds.
Not all homes include that. [music]
The dining space really opens up into
the living space. And it's [music] still
got a split floor plan, I'd say. Would
you say this is still kind of a split
floor plan? So, we have your [music]
guest bedrooms, your secondary bedrooms
on one side, and then the primary suite
on the other.
All three of these rooms [music] share
this bathroom.
It is only a single vanity.
But [music] really pretty tile
backsplash. They did the bronze fixtures
throughout. Plumbing fixtures, light
[music] fixtures.
Oh, we have Matt outside. Hana, it's my
partner. Brown carpet,
light [music] tan colored paint. So, if
you really love those warmer tones, this
is a good one. You have that linen
closet [music]
right off of the shared space for towels
or sheets or whatever any of these
wonderful people might need. This one is
the bigger of the three rooms.
I think this [music] would obviously
make a great bedroom of course, but also
probably a good flex room if you wanted
to do a
office or something. And it's also
[music] very wide.
This builder does include ceiling fans
in their
secondary rooms. [music]
Not all builders do that. So, you have
that ceramic tile in your wet areas and
your main living spaces and [music]
halls. And then the carpets in the
almost carpets in the bedrooms. Um, in
the living room you have the
Almost done, Matt.
We're not even outside.
In the living room, uh, they have the
the beamed ceilings
um or the accented [music] ceilings.
They do a lot of crown molding
throughout. Another pretty upgrade.
And then let's head on over to
Oh, this was a two and a half bath. For
some reason, I noted it as a two. So,
this is a two and a half bath. So,
that's really convenient. Uh, let's head
into the master.
So, [music] good size master. You don't
have an accented ceiling, per se, but
you do have recess [music] lighting.
This one is more long.
this home. Um, I would say that they do
set it up typically to where you'll have
be able to fit a king in that [music]
space with the windows on each side. And
they are phenomenal with their bathrooms
and closets. Uh, this one has [music]
two closets. So, Jack and Jill, Jill and
Jill, Jack and Jack, whatever your
uh scenario is, but really great closet
spaces and a beautiful bathroom. That
[music] center soaking tub just really
being the focal point of this bathroom.
Huge shower with dual shower heads,
dual vanities, one being slightly
bigger. We know that women would
typically claim [music] that vibe, but
your commode. And then, of course, you
do get a
linen closet on this one, too. So,
really great use of [music] bathroom
space. I'm curious. Do you love this
bathroom? Do you hate it? What do you
think?
And then we'll head on over to the
laundry room just so you can [music] see
what that space looks like.
This is a twocar garage
home, but small little laundry room. It
It is a laundry room, which is nice.
Inside the house, and a little bit
[music] of cabinet space,
twocar garage. And then the backyard is
well, the full lot itself [music] is. 21
acres. So,
really decent sized lot.
Covered patio. Small little covered
patio. Definitely enough to put a grill
and a little seating area out here. This
is [music] foursided masonry, so you
have brick on all four sides of the
home. You have full fencing,
um, privacy [music] fencing, and full
saw and irrigation front and back. So,
you're not going to have to be out here
handwatering, [music]
uh, your plants. But really cute home. I
love this builder. Let's go take a look
at the other two. We're on to house
number two. This is an Academy ISD, but
it's technically Temple. And so, I
really wanted to give you a good idea of
that $400,000 price point, but Academy
itself, Academy proper. so small I
couldn't find a spot-on 400,000. So,
this is basically Academy and again it
is [music] it is in Academy ISD. Biggest
difference between proper academy ISD
and this one is going to be that this
house [music] because it's in
technically in Temple is a 2.6 tax rate
whereas if you were truly in academy
Academy proper you'd have probably a tax
rate under [music] 2%. So that does make
a a bigger difference. Um, but this is a
completely different builder. This is
also a [music] production builder. So,
they're one of our areas. We have about
half dozen [music] bigger production
builders, meaning they kind of build in
bulk. Um, but [music] just different
things that they include in their home,
different price per square foot, and you
can really feel it and see it when you
walk through the home. And there are
different things that you get with
[music] those um different builders and
price points. So, this home in
particular, it's a four bed, three bath
home, roughly 2100 square f feet,
[music] brand spanking new as well,
except it's on a halfacre lot. So, I
think in comparing the last two, in
[music] addition to the differences in
area, last one being Troy, this one
being uh Little River Academy [music]
ISD, City of Temple, is that I feel like
you get a lot more [music] upgrades, so
to speak, in the last home. Um, but you
[music] get a much larger lot here. So,
you're on a 0.52 acre lot here, whereas
the last was 21. [music] So, the lot
size is going to be almost double. And
you can really feel that the backyard's
massive. [music] Um, we'll go ahead and
take a look and point out some of those
differences. Still a beautiful home. Um,
[music] to just totally different feel
of this builder, but I'm really excited
to show you. So, let's start at the
front.
This home is priced at $415,000.
Our last one was [music] priced at
$3.99. Again, almost spot-on. Uh similar
square footage, so the size is going to
[music] be similar. Bigger loft here,
different areas, but we'll see what you
think. We go inside. Let's go.
Okay. So, [music] a couple things I'd
like to point out is that um the
entryway is going to be [music] a little
bit different, too. The last one had
like that big pretty chandelier
entryway, but what I really like about
this floor plan is a lot of people will
come and they're looking for that
mother-in-law suite or that third full
bath, and this [music] one has it. So,
right at the front of the home, you have
one of your four [music] bedrooms with a
walk-in closet and [music] an attached
full bath. So, super convenient uh part
of [music] this home.
And then this is going to be, we'll just
take a peek in here. This is a side
entry garage. So if anyone's looking for
a side entry garage, you've got one
here, twocar.
Some other things to note for you. This
one does have fans in all of the
bedrooms. It doesn't include blinds. So,
as your realtor, I'm going to be telling
you those things that that come in
standard that um again, as your
representative, not the builder's
representative, we're going to try and
advocate for you to try and get you the
best deals. But [music] this one, our
last one had that ceramic tile, that
wood t
>> [music]
>> uh wood look tile. This one is actually
uh vinyl plank flooring
and in all the main living spaces
[music] and then the carpet in the
bedrooms. But this is your laundry
space. You have a good amount of
cabinets. It's much more cool toned in
this home. Light gray walls, almost
white, but light gray. You do have crown
molding throughout. Um, obviously where
your fridge would go. Some really fun
square accented [music]
tiles.
Also, the other home um had custom
cabinets. [music] These, which were
stained, these are hand painted
cabinets. So, a different feel and a
different look. And
the bot, these [music] are soft clothes.
And then throughout, we still have the
stainless steel appliances. So, what
comes included with your new home?
[music] Your microwaves if it's built
in, your stove, and your dishwasher. Um,
fridges [music] do not come standard in
a home. And then I like that this one
because we're kind of out in farmland,
they did a farm [music] feel accents on
a lot of things, including this
farmhouse sink. I like having this big
deep sink. And I really like the way
that this this layout is, is that you
can see into your backyard, which
currently overlooks some farmland.
[music] One thing to really point out on
this home, so whereas the last house had
full saw and irrigation, this one does
not. So, it stops um just about 5 ft off
the back patio, the grass. So, you
[music] would have to at some point
invest in putting in grass. I mean, I
guess you don't have to, but if you
wanted to, but it is [music] fully
fenced. And then we have Oh, look. We
have recessed lighting in your main
living space. I mean, super super open
here. I do love that.
Lots of light. We were just saying like
the lighting in here is fantastic. This
is a huge [music] living space. Put your
TV on this wall. Your couch is over
here. Or I guess the other way would
make sense, too. But I think funue wise,
you're not supposed to have your couches
when you walk in. But on this side, we
have your
your other full
bath over here, which is shared by these
just, you know, average standard sized
secondary bedrooms.
All bedrooms, did I say that? They do
include fans and they all have walk-in
closets. I noticed that about this floor
plan. So, that's really cool, too, is
not all floor plans are going to have
walk-in closets, [music] but this one
does. So, you have the granite
countertops throughout the tile in all
of your [music] wet areas other than
your kitchen. Good uh linen closet off
of these rooms
and
the primary bedroom. So, nothing fancy
per se about the ceilings, but this is a
very big space. It's a unique layout.
[music] So, I really feel like you could
probably only I mean, I guess you could
position your bed, your headboard there,
but that would kind of feel weird
walking in. I feel like it's supposed to
be over here.
But you also have dual dual closets. So,
two closets again, which is awesome.
And
great size
primary baths. [music] So, you have your
dual vanities.
soaking tub and walk-in shower, both
with [music] tile backsplash.
So, super functional, super cute.
And let's just take a look at how big
and awesome this backyard is.
This community is so new. And if you're
wondering with all this blue tape is,
that's something that they do right at
the end of a build to [music] mark
paint. And if you're buying a home, we
will do one of those as well where we
walk the house and point out any little
things because you're getting a brand
new home which comes with a perfect home
and all of the warranties. Um,
so yeah, you it just feel very far
farmland and rural, but you can see
where this grass really stops here and
you'd have to do that. Um, I do believe
this is on septic. [music] I think those
are septic sprayer heads out there,
which don't let that scare you. Again, I
wasn't from here, so I wasn't sure how I
felt about septic when I moved here,
[music] but it's very typical for larger
lots to have the septic.
That concludes our tour of this
beautiful home priced at $415,000
[music]
in Academy ISD/ City of Temple. Um, I'd
love to hear what you thought so far. Do
you like one or two? And at the end of
this video, after we look at this last
one in Nolanville, tell me what your
favorite is out of the three. Okay,
let's go.
>> This is the third and final stop on our
tour. This is in the Bella Charcoa
community in Nolanville, Texas. Very
similar in the square footage of the
last two we've seen. This one's at 2100
square ft, 4 bed, three bath. Totally
different builder. We have seen this one
before. And it's priced at $3.99.
It was originally $4.64, so they've come
down a ton on the price, which is great.
Can probably get some instant equity on
this one. And [music]
they're offering killer incentives to
buy this home. So, it's really awesome.
I can't wait to see what you think about
this one in comparison to the other two.
Let's go. Okay, so this is the entrance
of the home. long foyer area leading
into our main living space and
very as a concept. Um, one of the my
favorite parts of this builder is always
going to be their kitchen and their
backsplashes. Um, they also their
kitchen and their bathrooms. They also
have a really awesome patio door. These
things are [music] so heavy. Seen me
struggle uh wearing them in previous
stickers. But really quality. They open
all the way up. Just love them with some
light and air and really great for the
pretty malts and we have everything
[music] getting right in. So in the
kitchen, they do a great job of we have
our quartz countertops.
They're pulling in that two-toned
cabinet that is really trending. These
look painted. These look stained.
We have your microwave down below in the
island along with your dishwasher.
Stainless steel applying the fridge is
not included, but of course that was
something we can try and negotiate for
you. Besides the pantry, I'll just pop
this open for you.
But let's look down a quick little tour.
So, you don't have a formal dining room.
You have just eaten kitchen. And then we
have the there's three full bathrooms,
but this is one of them. uh with dual
vanities,
quartz countertops,
shower tub combo with a tile surround,
but similar to the last one we looked
at. Another great benefit benefit to
this one, you have bedroom one.
Another great benefit to this house is
also that third full bath inside of one
of the guest bedrooms. Um,
really desired and we we grabbed a
couple of them today to look at, but a
lot of I don't think there are a lot of
floor plans that typically have that in
this square footage. So that this
particular bedroom does.
You're going to have the carpet in all
of the bedrooms, the luxury vinyl plank
in all of the wet areas, uh, and all the
bathrooms, main living spaces, and
kitchen.
There are fans in all of the bedrooms.
They do not include blinds, but again,
I'm going to try and go this for you.
Oh, yeah.
Okay, you have electric fireplace.
There's not a lot of ton of gas any uh
the central Texas area. It does exist,
but if that's important, always bring
that up. Um, super functional laundry
room, good cabinet space, and even a
little folding area. I feel like they
did good use of this space.
And then the primary suite. This primary
suite is super uh bright. You have the
recess lighting, tons of window space
overlooking your backyard. I was kind of
surprised how big the backyard was on
this home. So, that's great.
And they always do great bathrooms. So,
you have this um nice [music] standalone
soaking tub
in here [music] with your jewel
vanities. Really pretty walk-in shower
with that herring bone green tile. Nice
great walk-in closet. I got the wall of
those. Okay.
And you notice what it looks like, so we
don't need to show you that.
And then we'll take a look at the
backyard. So again, the last backyard
does not have full solid irrigation.
This one does. the long
but how it's situated. Oh,
how it's situated. I mean, I felt the
back still.
So, again, you can see this slides all
the way open. Super nice.
Small little covered patio. You do you
do have full foursided brick,
full privacy vent thing. No trees or
anything back here, but it is fully
slotted in a great size. As our third
and final home of our tour, I'd love to
hear what you thought. Did you like
house number one in
um the more luxury builder on an average
size plot? Did you like number two in
the homestead big farm style home? Um
[music]
less luxury interior but a much larger
lot or this one here in Nolanville. Let
us know that in the comments below.
Thank you so much for touring these
three beautiful homes with us today. I
hope you had so much fun. I love showing
you this big variety and I hope you
found it helpful. If you would like any
more information on relocating to the
central Texas area, whether that's new
construction or resale, you can find all
my contact information below. You can
also head on over to my website
livinginctx.com.
Till next time.